Marco Aurélio

Junior DevOps Engineer

Rua Luís Soares Barbosa, 27, Braga, Braga - Portugal

About Me

26 years old, Brazilian, multilingual professional with a diverse set of skills, highly effective in fast-paced environments, I entered the IT area while still in high school. I have over six years of IT experience, working as a developer, database manager, operations, system analyst, and a variety of technologies.

My Links



GitHub



Soft Skills

- Proactive
- Resourceful and flexible
- Creative
- Problem-solving
- Strong communication
- Teamwork
- Highly effective in fast-paced environments
- Continuous improvement

Professional Skills

- T-SOL
- AWS
- GitHub
- Docker
- Linux
- Windows
- C#
- Kubernetes

Work Experience

2022 **DevOps | Personal Projects**

> Linux server administration and bash scripting to automate day to day admin tasks. Understanding of DevOps methodologies. Configuring VPCs, virtual networks and subnets on AWS and also EC2 Instances, EBS Volumes, ELB, S3 and Route53. Automated provisioning, such as Ansible (YAML) and Terraform. Creation and maintenance of CI/CD pipelines (Jenkins). GitHub version control system. Docker containers, image build. Kubernetes pods, replica sets and deployments.

2017-2019 Developer and System Consultant | DWT TI

> Development of improvements and customizations for the ERP TOTVS Protheus. Integration of third-party systems and webservices. Customer support and assistance. Implementation, installation, training, and the creation of user guides. Testing, approval and validation of system updates. SQL Server databases, administration, data analysis, query improvements, and automated backup routine optimization.

2015-2016 Operations and Systems Analyst | Gáutica

> Extensive testing on websites and applications created by the programming team, reporting any necessary fixes and improvements that were required. Deployment of system updates. Customer support, minor bug fixes. Infrastructure requirements and planning for website and application development. Creation of best practice guides for application development, application usage and internal systems. Query optimization, resource monitoring, database configuration and maintenance.

Administration and configuration of both Linux and Windows Server.

2014-2015 Junior Developer | Hábil Informática

> Development of reports for the ERP system. The system was built in Visual Basic and I was responsible for its migration to ASP.NET language. Performed face-to-face customer service, requirements analysis, infrastructure planning, system implementation as well as support for it, and, if needed, internal network configuration. Customizations and improvements for the ERP. Configuration of the SQL Server database, monitoring of used resources, optimization of queries for better performance and automated backup routines.

2012-2014 IT Assistant | Realcenter

> Computer maintenance, formatted and configured computers. I was introduced to Visual Basic and MSSQL, fixed minor bugs in the company system and extracted reports directly from the database. I helped the implementation and customization of an open-source helpdesk called GLPI Project, which is built in PHP and executed using Apache Tomcat in a Linux a server. Small system improvements and was responsible for the database management, backups, backups automation, replicas and monitoring.

Education

Ongoing DevOps Formation | Alura

2022 DevOps Beginners to Advanced | Udemy

> Linux, AWS, Scripting, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, K8s, N-Tier Projects. Certificate

2014-2015

Technologist Degree in System Analysis and Development | Unifted

Unfinished